Register of the Karl H. Von Wiegand papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1916-1961 (Boxes 4-23)
  - Shu tze (1), 1919
  - Siebert (1), 1922
  - Simon, H[ugo] F[erdinand] (3), 1924
  - Simon and Schuster (8), 1935-1952
  - Simons, [Walter] (6), 1920-1921
  - Smart Set (1), 1927
  - Smith, Charles A. (26), 1945-1947
  - Smith, Dewey W. (6), 1945
  - Smith, Max (3), 1924
  - Smith, U. Grant (1), 1919
  - Smith, Wiley (117), 1947-1949
  - Sokolsky, George E. (4), 1944-1957
  - Speidel, Hans (2), 1957
  - Spickernagel, Wilhelm (1), 1924
  - Spieker (2), 1924
  - Spiesser, Fritz (1), 1951
  - Stalin, Josef (1), 1951
  - Stallforth, F. (2), 1924
  - "Stan," incomplete identification (1), 1940
  - Stansbury, H. H. (13), 1922-1931
  - Stapleton, F. (3), 1946-1947
  - Steele, H. J. M. (1), 1924
  - Steiner, Rudolf (1), 1924
  - Stennes, Walther (1), 1949
  - Stinnes, Hugo (6), 1921-1924
  - Stockhammern, Franz von (29), 1922-1924
  - Stockton, Norman (1), 1938
  - Stohrer, Berthold A. von (13), 1929-1949
  - Stohrer, Maria-Ursula von (2), 1948-1954
  - Stone, Marvin (14), 1957
  - Stresemann, Gustav (2), 1924
  - Stritzel-Artstatt, Fritz (1), 1924
  - Strong, Eleanor (9), 1944-1946
  - Studnicki, Wladyslaw (1), 1949 (Box 21)
  - Sudermann, Hermann (2), 1922
  - Sweeny, Charles (6), 1935-1946
  - Sweetland, Reginald (2), 1928
  - Taesas, Loerenzo (1), 1935
  - Takla, G. B. (1), 1940
  - Talaat, Mehmed (1), 1920
  - Tanaka (1), 1929
  - Taylor, Keith (1), 1946
  - Terdegne (3), 1924
  - Theuer, Alfred (1), 1934
  - Theuer, Ilse (1), 1947
  - Thoemmes, Friedrich (3), 1955-1956
  - Thwaites, Norman G. (11), 1920-1929
  - Tietsort, Francis J. (1), 1929
  - Time (2), 1945
  - Tingley, K[atherine] (2), 1922
  - Tirpitz, Alfred von (14), 1920-1924
  - Tirpitz, W. (1), 1952
  - Tobey, Mark (2), 1958
  - Tolischus, Otto D. (36), 1924-1955
  - Torres, Jose Ribeiro (4), 1945-1947
  - Trebitsch-Lincoln, [Ignatius Timothy] (2), 1920
  - Trotskii, Lev (1), 1925
  - Tuck, Florence B. (5), 1944
  - Tyabjig, Badr-Ud-Din (2), 1959
  - Ullstein Verlag (3), 1924
  - Uno, "Buddy" (4), 1949-1950
  - Untermeyer, Samuel (6), 1921
  - Valier, Max (1), 1927
  - Van Ettisch, R. T. (3), 1944
  - Vanderbilt, Cornelius, Jr. (1), 1950
  - Van Voorhees, Edwin (3), 1945-1947
  - Varges, Ariel (11), 1921-1929
  - Veltheim-Ostrau, Hans Hasso (1), 1939
  - Viereck, George Sylvester (1), 1925
  - Virnich, Alfred (13), 1936-1960
  - Virnich, Mary "Molly" (21), 1932-1958
  - Vitali, Louis (1), 1948
  - Vogel (1), 1921
  - Voigt-Ruscheweyh (3), 1924
  - Walska, Ganna (4), 1924
  - Walter, Miriam R. (5), 1923
  - Walterspiel, Alfred (5), 1947-1948
  - Wang (1), undated
  - Wang, Ching-wei (2), 1932
  - Wangenheim (4), 1929
  - Watson, Victor (10), 1921-1924
  - Weigelt, Kurt (1), 1951
  - Weil (1), 1922
  - Weill, Harold (22), 1944-1960
  - Weisl, Wolfgang von (2), 1929
  - Welles, Bella Fromm (2), 1959-1960
  - Wells, Anna (5), 1948
  - Wells, Linton (1), 1954
  - Wenig, Richard (303), 1923-1960
    - Undated (Box 22)
    - 1923-1938
    - 1947-1949
    - 1950-1959
    - 1960
  - Wenner-Gren, A. L. (2), 1951
  - Wenzlick, Ly (4), 1934
  - Westfall, E. A. (2), 1921, 1931
  - Weyer (2), 1924
  - Weyland, Paul (3), 1950
  - Whelan, Edward J. (6), 1945
  - White, Katherina J. "Jessie" (46), 1929-1955
  - White, M. A. (148), 1930-1935
  - White, Thomas J. (9), 1931-1947 (Box 23)
  - White, William (137), 1931, 1940-1955
  - Whiting, Frances (4), 1925, 1945
  - Wiedemann, Fritz (3), 1948
  - [Wiegand], Anna (10), 1945-1947
  - Wiegand, Gordon (3), 1945-1948
  - Wiegand, Inez (6), 1923-1955
  - Wiegand, Lee (2), 1945
  - Wiegand, Norma (4), 1948
  - Wiegand, Norman (33), 1919-1955
  - Wiegand, Perle (2), undated
  - Wiegand, Rex S. (3), 1944-1955
  - Wieprecht, J., 1921-1923
  - Wiley, Robert H. (10), 1941-1944
  - Wilhelm, Kronprinz (20), with aides (36), 1919-1940
  - Willicombe, Joseph (35), 1927-1944
  - Wirth, Josef (2), 1920, 1922
  - Witos, [Wincenty] (1), 1921
  - Wood, Lee B. (2), 1957
  - Woolard, Warden (6), 1959
  - Woon, Basil (3), 1923
  - Wronsky, Martin (1), 1935
  - Wu, [Te-chen] (2), 1931
  - Yarnell (1), 1938
  - Young, George (1), 1920
  - Young, James (2), 1946
  - Zia, M. (3), 1920-1921
  - Ziegfeld, A. H. (1), 1947
  - Zimmermann, Eugen (6), 1920-1922
  - Zimmermann, Job (1), 1947
  - Zolling, Ernst (2), 1954
- SPEECHES AND WRITING, 1913-1961 (Boxes 24-48)
  Drafts and printed copies of news dispatches, newspaper and magazine articles, essays, notes, and autobiographical writings by Karl H. von Wiegand, as well as interviews conducted by him with political figures, arranged chronologically.
  - United Press cable log, carbon copies in bound volume, 1913-1914 (Box 24)
  - Newspaper articles, New York Sun, clippings in bound volume, 1914
  - Interview with Pope Benedict XV, New York World, photocopies (2), 1915 April 11
  - Newspaper articles, New York World, clippings in bound volume, 1916
  - News dispatches, New York Sun, carbon copies, 1919 June-August
    - General
    - Re Bettmann-Hollweg
    - Re Hindenburg interview
    - Re von Tirpitz
    - Re Wilhelm II
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1919-1920
  - Untitled draft, carbon copy, 1921 April 27
  - Interview with Otto Gessler, typescript, 1921
  - Interview with Josef Wirth, typescript, circa 1922 (Box 25)
  - Dispatches from Constantinople, carbon copies, 1922
  - Dispatches re Genoa Conference, carbon copies, 1922
  - Newspaper articles, clippings
    - 1922 April-August
    - 1922 September-October
    - 1922 November-December
    - 1923 January-June
    - Re Tirpitz, 1923 June 17
    - 1923 July-December (Box 26)
    - 1924 January-June
    - 1924 November-December (Box 27)
    - 1925 January-June
    - 1925 July-December
  - News dispatch re Mussolini, 1926 February 25 (Box 28)
  - Newspaper articles, clippings
    - 1926 January-June
    - 1926 July-December
    - Re Tirpitz, 1926 November
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1927
  - Newspaper articles, clippings
    - 1927 January-June (Box 29)
    - 1927 July-December
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1928
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1928
    - General
    - Re trans-Atlantic crossing of the Graf Zeppelin, 1928 October 16
      - New York American
      - New York Journal
      - Chicago Herald Examiner
  - "A Voyage on a Zeppelin," panorama (with Hettie F. Cattell), printed copy, 1928 November 10 (Box 30)
  - The First Trans-Oceanic Voyage of a Commercial Air-Liner (with Grace Drummond-Hay), printed copies (7), 1928
  - News dispatches, primarily from the Graf Zeppelin, carbon copies, 1929
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1929
    - General
    - Re Graf Zeppelin
  - Interview questions, carbon copies, 1929
  - Interview with Adolf Hitler, photocopy, 1929 December
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1930
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1930
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1931
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1931
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1932
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1932
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1933
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1933
  - Notes re E. Hanfstaengl, typescript, 1933
  - Notes re Italo Balbo, typescript, 1934 June
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1934
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1934
  - Autobiography, outline, circa 1935
  - Notes re state of mind in Rome and re Mussolini, typescript, 1935 August 19
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1935
    - January-June (Box 31)
    - July-December
      Primarily from Addis Ababa.
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1935
  - News dispatches from the L.S. Hindenburg, 1936
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1936
  - "Von Wiegand Tells Difficulties of Covering Spain's Civil War," Editor and Publisher, printed copy, 1936 August 15
  - "I Cover the Spanish Front," Cosmopolitan, 1936 December
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1938
  - Newspaper dispatches, carbon copies, 1938
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1938
  - "Hitler Foresees His End," Cosmopolitan, printed copies, 1939 April, May
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1939
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1939
  - Notes re Italy, typescript, 1940 April 23 (Box 32)
  - "Europe for the Europeans," by Adolf Hitler, answers prepared in English for interview with von Wiegand, typescript, 1940 June 11
  - "Luftwaffe gegen Seemacht! Ein Interview mit Reichsmarschal Hermann Goering" (Airforce versus sea power), typescript (carbon copy), 1940 July 27
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1940
  - Newspaper articles, clippings [See: Box 48], 1940
  - "Analysis of Dictators," typescript (photocopy), 1941 January
  - Diary from Shanghai and Manila, typescript (carbon copies), 1941
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1941
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1941 (Box 85)
  - Diary from Manila, typescript, 1942
  - Diary from Shanghai, typescript, 1942
  - Diary from Shanghai, typescript, 1943 (Box 33)
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1943
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1943
  - "Europe After the War," typescript (photocopy), 1944
  - Untitled essay re Europe, typescript, circa 1955
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1944
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1944
    - January-March
    - April-June (Box 34)
    - July-August
    - September-December
  - Notes, miscellaneous, typescript, 1944
  - Newspaper articles [See: Box 48]
  - Untitled article, carbon copy, 1945 (Box 35)
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1945
    - January-June
    - July-August
    - September-December (Box 36)
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1946
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1946
    - January-February
    - March-June
    - July-August (Box 37)
    - September-December
  - News dispatches, carbon and mimeographed copies, 1947
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1947
    - January-June
    - July-December (Box 38)
  - News dispatches, carbon and mimeographed copies, 1948
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1948
    - January-June
    - July-September (Box 39)
    - October-December
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1949
  - Newspaper articles, 1949
    - January-June
    - July-September
    - October-December (Box 40)
  - Interview with Francisco Franco, carbon copy, circa 1950
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1950
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1950
    - January-March
    - April-September (Box 85)
    - October-December (Box 41)
  - News dispatches, carbon copies, 1951
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1951
    - January-March
    - April-June
    - July-September
    - October-December
  - News dispatches, mimeographed and carbon copies, 1952 (Box 42)
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1952
    - January-March
    - April-June
    - July-September
    - October-December
  - News dispatches, mimeographed and carbon copies, 1953 (Box 43)
  - Newspaper articles, 1953
    - January-March
    - April-June
    - July-September
    - October-December
  - News dispatches, carbon and mimeographed copies, 1954 (Box 44)
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1954
    - January-June
    - July-December
  - News dispatches, carbon and mimeographed copies, 1955 (Box 45)
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1955
    - January-June
    - July-December
  - News dispatches, carbon and mimeographed copies, 1956
  - Newspaper articles, 1956
    - January-June
    - July-December (Box 46)
  - News dispatches, carbon and mimeographed copies, 1957
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1957
    - January-June
    - July-December
  - News dispatches, carbon and mimeographed copies, 1958
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1958.
  - "Informationsgespraech," transcript of conversation with Konrad Adenauer, typescript, 1959 June 4 (Box 47)
  - News dispatches, mimeographed and carbon copies, 1959
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1959
  - News dispatches, mimeographed and carbon copies, 1960
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, 1960
  - News dispatches, mimeographed and carbon copies, 1961
  - News dispatches, mimeographed and carbon copies, undated
  - Newspaper articles, clippings, undated
  - Miscellaneous notes, typescript and holograph, undated
  - Autobiography and eyewitness accounts of historical events, undated
    Drafts, notes, and background material, typescripts and holographs.
    - "An Autobiographical Effort"
    - Background notes
    - "Outline of the Memoirs of Karl H. von Wiegand"
      - Typescript
      - Dictaphone belts (10)
    - Account of interview with Pope Benedict XV
    - Account of interview with Hindenburg
    - Account of Interview with von Tirpitz, with background material
    - Account of interview with Crown Prince Wilhelm
  - Newspaper articles, mounted clippings and photocopies, 1928, 1940-1941, 1944-1945
    - New York American (15), trans-Atlantic flight of Graf Zeppelin, 1928 October 16 (Box 48)
    - San Francisco Examiner (3), interview with Adolf Hitler, 1940 June 14
    - Los Angeles Examiner (2), San Francisco Examiner (3), re Japanese deadline on negotiations, 1941 November 2
    - Los Angeles Examiner (2), San Francisco Examiner (3), re atomic energy and secret weapons, 1944 January 2
    - Los Angeles Examiner (2), San Francisco Examiner (3), New York Journal American (2), re Soviet Union, 1944 January 16
    - Los Angeles Examiner (2), San Francisco Examiner (3), re Soviet Union, 1944 May 14
    - San Francisco Examiner (3), 1944 May 21
    - Los Angeles Examiner (2), San Francisco Examiner (3), 1944 June 4
    - Los Angeles Examiner (2), San Francisco Examiner (3), 1944 June 18
    - Los Angeles Examiner (2), San Francisco Examiner (3), 1944 July 2
    - Los Angeles Examiner (2), 1944 August 20
    - Los Angeles Examiner (2), 1944 August 21
    - Miscellaneous mounted clippings (227 leaves), 1944-1945
- SUBJECT FILE, 1911-1961 (Boxes 49-81)
  Memoranda, essays, correspondence, clippings, and pamphlets, arranged alphabetically by subject. Includes papers of journalist Grace M. Drummond-Hay.
  - Afghanistan (Box 49)
  - Africa
  - Afro-Asian Peoples Solidarity Conference
  - Air-ships
    - Eckener, Hugo
    - Memorabilia and miscellaneous correspondence re Graf Zeppelin
    - Telegrams re Graf Zeppelin, 1929
    - Printed material
      - Allen, Hugh, The Story of the Airship, 1931 (Box 50)
      - Berliner Illustrierte Zeitung, "Dar Graf Zeppelin Weltflug" (Around the world flight of the Graf Zeppelin), 1929 September 15
      - Brandt, Rolf, "Mit Dr. Eckener nach America," Die Woche, 1928 November 3
      - Bruer, Carl, Erste Fahrt des Luftschiffes Hindenburg nach Nordamerika und zurueck (First flight of the airship Hindenburg to America and back), 1936
      - Dettmann, Mit dem "Zeppelin" nach America: Das Wunder von Himmel und Ozean (With the "Zeppelin" to America: The miracle of sky and ocean), 1929
      - Geisenheyner, Max, Mit "Graf Zeppelin" um die Welt (with Graf Zeppelin around the world), 1929
      - Goodyear Zeppelin Corporation, ZRS-4 Ring Laying: America in the Skyways, 1929
      - Megias, Jeronimo, La primera vuelta al mundo en el "Graf Zeppelin" (The first flight of the Graf Zeppelin around the world), 1929
      - Die Woche, "21 Tage Weltgeschichte" (21 days of world history), 1929 September 4 (Box 51)
      - Die Woche, "Zeppelin faehrt um die Welt" (Zeppelin travels around the world) (4), 1929
      - Newspaper clippings re trans-Atlantic flight of the Graf Zeppelin, 1928
        - October 6-10
        - October 11-15
        - October 16-20
        - October 21-30 (Box 52)
        - November 1
      - Newspaper clippings re world flight of the Graf Zeppelin
        - 1929
        - 1930
      - Newspaper clippings re flight of the airship Hindenburg to the United States, 1936
  - Alien Property Custodian Report, 1919 (Box 53)
  - Arabische Korrespondenz, 1958-1960
  - Art
  - Asia
  - Asia, South East
  - Austria
  - Aviation
  - Balkans (Box 54)
  - Bauer, Max
  - Beattie, Edward William
  - Belgium
  - Bergdoll-Griffis case
    Correspondence, clippings, and memorabilia.
  - "Die Bormann Vermerke" (the Bormann notes), typescript
  - Bruening, Heinrich
  - Bulgaria
  - China
    - General
    - Newspaper clippings
    - Japanese in China, 1932 (Box 55)
  - Collins, Thomas
  - Cyprus
  - Czechoslovakia
  - Dodd, William E.
  - Drummond-Hay, Grace M.
    - Biographical file
    - Memorabilia
    - Speeches and writings
      - News dispatches
      - Newspaper articles
      - Interview with Italo Balbo (Box 56)
      - Interview with Magda Lupescu
      - Interview with Stresemann
      - Interview with Zaghloul Pasha
      - "World Affairs," The Sphere
      - Miscellaneous
      - Diary, 1941
      - Diary, 1943
    - Correspondence
      - Address lists
      - General
      - The Daily Express
      - A-B-C (Box 57)
      - D-E-F
      - G-H-I
      - J-K-L
      - M-N-O
      - P-Q-R
      - S-T-U
      - V-W-X-Y-Z
    - Background material and clippings (Box 58)
  - Economics
  - Egypt
    - General
    - Pamphlets
    - Pamphlets - The Sphere and Le Progres Egyptien (Box 48)
    - Newspaper clippings
      - 1924 (Box 59)
      - 1947
      - 1952
      - 1953
      - 1954
      - 1955
      - 1956
      - 1957 (Box 60)
      - 1958
      - 1959
      - 1960
  - Ehrhardt, Ludwig (Box 61)
  - Escherich, Georg
  - Europa-Briefe
  - Europe, East
  - Finland
  - France
  - Fritsch, [Werner von]
  - Genoa Conference, 1922
  - Germany
    - General (Box 62)
    - Magazines
      - Der Adler, "Legion Condor an der Front,", 1939
      - Illustrierter Beobachter, "Unser Fuehrer zum 50. Geburtstag,", 1939
      - Kladderadatsch, 1939 January 22
      - Koelnische Illustriete Zeitung, "Schwerste Artillerie,", 1940 April 4
      - Das schwarze Corps, "Mein Fuehrer,", 1939 April 20
      - Die Wehrmacht, "Wir kaempfen in Spanien,", 1939
      - Die Woche, 1940
    - Newspaper clippings
      - 1920
      - 1923
      - 1926
      - 1927
      - 1930
      - 1931
      - 1932
      - 1933
      - 1934 (Box 63)
      - 1935
      - 1936
      - 1937
      - 1938
      - 1939
      - 1940
      - 1944
      - 1945
      - 1946
      - 1947
      - 1948
      - 1949
      - 1950
      - 1951
      - 1952 (Box 64)
      - 1953
      - 1954
      - 1955
      - 1956
      - 1957
      - 1958
      - 1959
      - 1960
      - 1961
    - Newspapers
      - Berliner Boersen-Zeitung, 1934 August 3-5
      - Berliner Lokal-Anzeiger, 1939 April 18, July 4
      - Berliner Montagspost, 1934 August 6
      - Berliner Tageblatt, 1923 February 28, 1934 August 3, 4
      - Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 1934 August 2, 4, 5, 7, 8, 1935 May 2, 1939 February 24, July 5
      - Deutsche Allegmeine Zeitung, 1944 December 20, 23, 1945 January 13 (Box 65)
      - Militaer-Wochenblatt, 1939 May 5
      - National-Zeitung, 1933 September 28, 1935 June 15, 1939 April 5, July 18
      - Das neue Tagebuch, Paris-Amsterdam, 1934 August 11, 1935 March 23, June 8, 15, 1939 July 1, 15, 29
      - Pariser Tageszeitung, 1939 March 16, 17
      - Voelkischer Beobachter
        - 1933
        - 1934
        - 1939
        - 1945
      - Vossische Zeitung, 1933 July 15
  - Germany, East
  - Goering, Hermann
  - Great Britain
    - General (Box 66)
    - Newspaper clippings
  - Greece
  - Haddon, Clarence Gordon
  - Harden, Maximillian
  - Hawaii
  - Hearst, William Randolph
  - Hearst Corporation
  - Hearst editorials
    - 1935
    - 1949
    - 1950
    - 1951 January-May
    - 1951 June-September (Box 67)
    - 1952
    - 1953
    - 1954
    - Dispatches by W. R. Hearst, Jr., from the Soviet Union, 1955
    - 1955
    - 1956
    - 1957
    - 1958
    - 1959 (Box 68)
    - 1960
    - 1961
  - Historiography
  - Hitler, Adolf
  - Hong Kong
  - Hoover, Herbert
  - Hungary
  - India
    - General
    - "Indiagram" (Box 69)
  - Indonesia
  - Iran
  - Iraq
  - Ireland
  - Israel
    - General
    - Newspaper clippings
  - Italy
    - General
    - Newspaper clippings
  - Japan (Box 70)
  - Jews
  - Journalism
  - Kennedy, John
  - Kerr, Caroline
  - Khrushchev, Nikita
  - Korea
  - League of Nations
  - Lippman, Walter
  - Literature (Box 71)
  - Lithuania
  - Ludendorff, Erich
  - Marshall Plan
  - Medicine
  - Mediterranean
  - Middle East
    - General
    - Newspaper clippings
  - Miscellaneous (Box 72)
  - Netherlands
  - Oil
  - Oswald, Lydia
  - Overseas Press Club
    - 1959
    - 1960
    - 1961
  - Pakistan
  - Papen, Franz von
  - Philippine Islands
  - Philosophy
  - Poland
  - Portugal (Box 73)
  - Psychology
  - Religion
  - Romania
  - Russia
    - General
    - 1929
    - 1930
    - 1931
    - 1932
    - 1934
    - 1935
    - 1936
    - 1939
    - 1944
    - 1945
    - 1946
    - 1947
    - 1948
    - 1949
    - 1950
    - 1951 (Box 74)
    - 1952
    - 1953
    - 1954
    - 1955
    - 1956
    - 1957
    - 1958
    - 1959
    - 1960
  - Scandinavia
  - Seeckt, Hans von
  - Sokolsky, George, editorials
    - 1952
    - 1953
    - 1954
    - 1955
    - 1956
    - 1957 (Box 75)
    - 1958
    - 1959
    - 1960 January-May
    - 1960 August-December
    - 1961 (Box 76)
  - South America
  - Spain
  - Switzerland
  - Syria
  - Technology
    - General
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 77)
  - Tibet
  - Tolischus, O. D.
  - Turkey
  - Tyrol
  - United States
    - General
    - 1943
    - 1944
    - 1945
    - 1946
    - 1947
    - 1948
    - 1949
    - 1950
    - 1951 (Box 78)
    - 1952
    - 1953
    - 1954
    - 1955
    - 1956
    - 1957
    - 1958
    - 1959
    - 1960
    - 1961
  - U.S. Navy
  - Universal Service
  - Vietnam
  - Wilhelm II
  - Wilhelm, Kronprinz
  - Wilson, Woodrow
  - Women, status of
  - World politics
    - 1924
    - 1928
    - 1929
    - 1930
    - 1932
    - 1933
    - 1934 (Box 79)
    - 1935
    - 1936
    - 1937
    - 1938
    - 1940
    - 1943
    - 1944
    - 1945
    - 1946
    - 1947 (Box 80)
    - 1948
    - 1949
    - 1950
    - 1952
    - 1953
    - 1955
    - 1956
    - 1957 (Box 81)
    - 1958
    - 1959
    - 1960
  - World War I
  - World War II
    - General
    - 1944
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings
  - Yalta, Crimean Conference, 1945
  - Zita, Empress
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1911-circa 1960 (Boxes 82-83, Photo file)
  3,357 prints, 17 negatives, 1 glass negative, and 5 drawings, arranged by subject.
  - Photograph albums (4) relating to World War I (Boxes 82-83)
  - 6 prints, early portraits of von Wiegand, undated (Envelope A)
  - 99 prints, portraits and snapshots of von Wiegand, undated (Envelope B-C)
  - 43 prints of family members, undated (Envelope D)
  - 23 prints of Grace M. Drummond-Hay, undated (Envelope E)
  - 89 prints of Heston Air Park, undated (Envelope F)
  - 362 prints relating to the airship Graf Zeppelin, 1928-1929 (Envelope G-J)
  - 17 negatives of articles by von Wiegand, undated (Envelope K)
  - 51 prints, mainly portraits, including Count and Countess Courten, Gen. Bernhardi, Graf Brockderff-Rantzau, Wilhelm Werner, Samoilovich, undated (Envelope L)
  - 52 prints of W. R. Hearst, Marion Davies, and San Simeon, undated (Envelope M)
  - 15 prints of Rudolf Nebel working with experimental rockets, undated (Envelope N)
  - 583 prints of China, undated (Envelope O-S)
  - Glass plate negative depicting Chiang Kai-shek and Soong May-ling on their wedding day, undated (Envelope T)
  - 97 prints of Japan, undated (Envelope U)
  - 67 prints of Angor-Wat, undated (Envelope V)
  - 66 prints of Burma and Malaya, undated (Envelope W)
  - 50 prints of Ceylon, etc., undated (Envelope X)
  - 100 prints of Egypt, undated (Envelope Y)
  - 93 prints of the Middle East, undated (Envelope Z)
  - 107 prints of South Africa, circa 1911 (Envelope AA)
  - 161 prints of Africa, undated (Envelope BB)
  - 9 prints of North Africa, undated (Envelope CC)
  - 82 prints of Europe, undated (Envelope DD)
  - 42 prints of Vaduz, undated (Envelope EE)
  - 50 prints of Tenerife, undated (Envelope FF)
  - 18 prints of Russia, undated (Envelope GG)
  - 18 prints of Havana, Lisbon, Angora, undated (Envelope HH)